More heinous criminals will show up.
还会有更多重案犯出现的
This team is always working very hard.
这个小组总是那么勤奋
But there still has to be someone preparing for what may happen.
但仍然需要有人 时刻准备着应对未知情况
We need you to take on a case.
我们需要你接一个案子
He and his wife were murdered in their home two weeks ago.
两周前他们夫妻俩在家中遇害
There was cash lying around, but he didn't even touch it.
这些现金这么显眼 可他碰都没碰
They think it's an act of resentment masked as a burglary.
他们认为是伪装成入室盗窃的仇杀
What? It's clean.
什么？很干净呢
The victims were overpowered without any sort of resistance.
受害者没有任何抵抗 应该是一击毙命
GUNGOK-DONG FAMILY MURDER CASE
（郡谷洞全家被杀案 2003年9月24号）
A type of systematic crime committed according to a plan.
按计划实施的系统性犯罪类型
Is this a way of expressing
是凶手因为仇恨
the culprit's emotions caused by a grudge they hold?
而泄愤的杀人方式吗？
Hiking shoes.
登山鞋
This one is from Suseong-dong, Gangnam.
第一个是寿城洞的
And this one is from Gungok-dong, Jongno.
第二个是郡谷洞
They're from different areas but the same culprit?
所在辖区不同 但是是同一个凶手？
JINJUNG-DONG, GANGNAM-GU
（江南区晋中洞）
There was another case in Jinjung-dong.
晋中洞又有一个案子
You're not an investigator. Why?
你不是调查人员 凭什么让你进？
Please. I must check the crime scene.
拜托了 我一定要检查案发现场
Hey. Didn't you hear me?
喂 你没听见吗？
I told you to get lost, you bastard!
我让你走开 混蛋
Damn it.
该死
This is important.
这事非常重要
The victim was hit by a blunt weapon.
受害者遭钝器打击
And the safe wasn't touched either.
保险箱也没有碰过
The culprit went to different areas and his only purpose was to kill.
凶手在不同地区流窜 他的唯一目的就是杀人
This is the third murder.
这是第三起谋杀案
It's a serial murder.
这是一个连环杀人案
HWANGHWA-DONG, JONGNO-GU
（钟路区黄花洞）
Hurry to the scene in Hwanghwa-dong.
请立刻赶往黄花洞现场
A senior citizen was murdered.
一位老人被杀害
Why did he suddenly start a fire?
为什么他会突然放火？
He's never done that before.
他之前从没那么干过
I'm sure he came across an unexpected situation.
他肯定遇到了意外情况
He either wanted to destroy unwanted traces
他要么是为了毁掉多余的痕迹
or it could've been his trace.
要么就是为了抹掉自己的痕迹
It's CCTV footage.
我是说监控录像
We got a shot of the back of the culprit.
我们拍到了罪犯的背影
Let's put out an APB.
我们来发布全境通缉吧
You want us to do that with just the footage that shows his back?
你想让我们拿着一张监控录像里的 背影照片去公开通缉吗？
Are you suggesting that we give him a warning
你是建议我们给他一点警告
-that he could get caught? -That's correct.
-告诉他我们能逮到他吗？ -就是这样
The only way to prevent him from committing the next murder is this.
阻止他犯下新的谋杀案的 唯一方法只有这个
The footage shows a man in a black jacket walking.
监控录像拍到了一个 穿着黑色夹克衫的行人背影
The police have identified this man in the footage…
警方已经确认录像中的该男子…
Even after you put out the APB…
尽管你们发布了公开通缉后…
-At least share the information! -Tell us anything.
-至少公布点信息啊！ -告诉我们吧
It's been over three months
已经过去三个月了
and the police still don't have a single lead on the culprit.
警方还是没有任何关于罪犯的线索
The decision for an open search.
公开通缉决定
Is this the police's lifeline or is this the beginning of doom?
这是警察的救命稻草 还是厄运的开始？
Did he give up on committing another crime to hide?
他是放弃作案躲起来了吗？
Or is he still planning another crime?
还是他仍在计划一次新的作案？
You never miss a day.
你一天都不落下啊
We never know when the crimes will start again.
我们永远都不知道 犯罪会在什么时候发生
We will catch him. Certainly.
我们会抓到他的 一定会的
What if the culprit changed the MO?
如果罪犯改变了作案手法呢？
What do we do then?
那我们该如何是好？
-What are the police doing? -Exactly.
-警察都在干什么？ -就是
They still haven't been able to catch a punk like this.
他们还是没能抓到这样的混蛋
-I know, right? -Yes.
-我说对吧？ -嗯
STABBED WITH A CAMPING KNIFE
（推定使用野营用刀）
FEBRUARY 12, 2004 SINHEUNG 2-DONG, YEONGDEUNGPO-GU
（2004年2月12号 永登浦区新兴二洞）
MILK
（牛奶）
DAILY CASE REPORT
（每日案件报告）
VICTIM PARK SO-EUN
（受害者 朴素恩）
THE VICTIM WAS ATTACKED ON FEBRUARY 12, 2004,
（受害者于2004年2月12号 在回家路上遭到袭击）
IN THE CHEST, STOMACH, AND SIDE ON HER WAY HOME
（胸口 腹部以及身体两侧）
It's so cold. Hey, it's warm inside.
好冷啊 屋里真暖和
-You're early. -You're here.
-来着这么早 -你在啊
You got here so early.
你那么早就到了啊
-Yes, I did. -It's freezing.
-是的 -太冷了
-It's really cold out, isn't it? -Yes.
-外面可真冷 对吧？ -对
Inspector Song.
宋警卫
Last week, I made a wish while looking at the first full moon of the year.
上周我望着今年的第一轮满月许了愿
What?
什么？
It's been four years since I joined the team.
我来这里已经有四年了
I really hope you can start
我真希望从今年开始
talking to me casually this year.
你能随意地跟我交流
Hey, come on. It's been four years.
喂 已经四年了啊
Woo-ju says it's his wish.
又不是地球的愿望
Woo-ju, our universe! Can't you grant his wish?
宇宙 是我们的宇宙！ 你就不能帮他满足心愿吗？
Was that a joke?
是在开玩笑吗？
I'll start talking casually then.
那之后我就开始随意地说话好了
Really?
真的吗？
Had I known it'd be this easy, I would've brought it up long ago.
如果我知道这是那么简单 我早就提出来了
I should've done this long ago.
我早该这么做了
It took too long.
时间太长了吧
Are you playing favorites?
你是在厚此薄彼吗？
You don't laugh at my jokes.
我讲的笑话你不笑
But you laughed at his lame joke.
他蹩脚的笑话却能逗笑你
He laughed because he likes me, not because I'm funny.
他笑是因为他喜欢我 不是因为我好笑
That's right.
没错
You must be a snowflake because he fell for you.
你们非要一大早就这么肉麻吗？
You're so mean.
真的过分
Anything showing a similar pattern?
今天也是以相同的形式上传的吗？
-No, not the same pattern. -Let's see.
-没有一样的形式 -让我看看
DAILY CASE REPORT
（每日案件报告）
An assault case…
暴力袭击案件…
Nothing.
没有啊
I hope he has stopped.
但愿他已经收手了
Whatever he may be doing,
无论他在做什么
we just need to do our job.
我们只要做好我们的工作
We got this.
加油
PROFILING (CRIME ANALYSIS) REPORT
（犯罪侧写报告书）
Why are you going through the profiling report?
你为什么在看分析报告？
Hoping to find some clues.
想要找点线索出来
Clues, my foot.
线索个头
Thanks to that idiot, Song Ha-young,
多谢那个白痴宋霞永
the police were criticized for being incompetent.
警察都被骂成无能之徒了
And now, the culprit has gone into hiding.
而且现在 罪犯已经躲起来消失了
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
Why do you care?
你知道干吗？
Oh, it's a record.
哦 破纪录了
He got here less than 30 minutes ago.
这次不到30分钟就走了
HWANGHWA-DONG MURDER
（黄花洞谋杀案）
Time is ticking, but we have no idea where this scum is.
时间在一分一秒地过去 可我们还不知道这个混蛋在哪里
-Oh, you're early. -Hello.
-你们来得可真早 -你们好
How have you been?
近日可好？
Woo-ju, say hello before you step out.
宇宙 进门前要先问候
Nice to meet you.
很高兴认识你们
This case made me feel the need to study, so I'll be joining you today.
这起案件让我有了学习的动力 所以今天我要加入你们
Good thinking.
想法不错啊
-I'll be right back. -Okay, hurry.
-我去去就回 -好的 快去吧
We'll get started when Woo-ju gets back.
宇宙回来后我们就开始
-Take a seat. -You can sit here.
-坐吧 -请来这里坐
Professors.
专家们
There are so many scumbags in this world
这世上混蛋太多了
that we've got lots of studying to do.
所以我们才有那么多研究要做啊
About the serial murder of rich seniors.
关于谋杀富有老人的连环案
The weapon hasn't been identified yet, right?
还没找到凶器对吗？
No, not yet.
没错
What causes that triangle-shaped scar?
那种三角形伤疤是什么弄出来的呢？
We've been checking
我们已经试过了所有能想到的钝器
The abrasion, hypodermal bleeding,
擦伤 皮下出血
and laceration.
以及撕裂伤
Also considering the depth of the dent, it's not a light weapon.
结合伤口深度考虑的话 凶器的质量不会很轻
Considering the weight and force, a steel hammer would be a match,
考虑其重量和力度的话 铁锤是最合适的
but they're usually either round or sharp.
但它们通常不是圆头的就是尖头的
And It's not easy to carry it around as it's long.
而且因为它把手很长 所以携带起来并不容易
Captain Kook, I'm beginning to think that your guess may be correct.
国组长 我开始怀疑 你的猜想是否是成立的了
It makes me anxious.
这让我很不安
That the culprit made the weapon?
你是指罪犯自己制造了凶器？
If that's true, we can't identify it.
如果事实如此的话 我们就无法辨识它了
I've never seen anyone put so much effort into murder.
我还从没见过有人在谋杀案中 如此费心思
-I bought it. -It's so cold.
-我买的 -太冷了
Anyway, is the lady in that building okay?
不过住在那栋楼的女士还好吗？
-I think so. -My goodness.
-我想是的 -我的天啊
What if she'd died--
如果她死了的话
-That building. -Goodness.
-那栋楼 -天啊
What happened?
出什么事了吗？
Last night, a lady on the second floor nearly died.
昨晚二楼的一位女士差点死掉了
Thank goodness she didn't die.
谢天谢地她还活着
A stranger followed her and stabbed her.
有陌生人尾随了她 还拿刀捅她
She didn't die?
她没死吗？
She's still alive?
她还活着？
Richard Chase was also abused by his parents as a kid.
理查德·蔡斯也是在其孩童时期 遭受了父母的虐待
He wet his bed, committed arson, and abused animals,
他会尿床 纵火并虐待小动物
which are common in serial killers.
这些是连环杀人犯的共性
He killed adults and children in a brutal manner.
他用残忍的手法杀害成年人和小孩
He didn't hold a grudge against them.
他对他们没有怨恨
Why did he brutally murder victims chosen at random?
为什么他要随意残杀那些人呢？
Most murderers like him usually kill for their own pleasure and enjoyment.
大多数像他那样的杀人犯 杀人都是为了自己的快乐享受
For pleasure, not because of anger?
为了快乐 不是出于愤怒吗？
That is the most frightening part.
这就是最令人恐怖的部分
It means killing makes them happy.
这意味着杀人能使他们快乐
Killing satisfies them,
杀人能给他们带来快感
so they can't stop.
所以他们停不下来
They become bolder, looking for bigger pleasures.
他们会越来越大胆 并去寻找更大的乐趣
Correct.
没错
That's why he mutilated the body and practiced cannibalism.
所以他才会去肢解尸体并尝试吃人肉
Sexually deviant killers tend to commit such acts.
性功能异常的杀手 往往也会做出这样的行为
So Richard Chase's cases are often categorized as lust murders
所以理查德·蔡斯的案子 经常被归类为欲望谋杀
and as sexual homicides.
以及性谋杀
Sexual homicides?
性谋杀？
That's right.
没错
The way he mutilated his victims doesn't show a pattern.
他用不同的方式截肢他的受害者们
There's no pattern at all.
根本没有固定模式
He didn't know much about human anatomy,
他并不了解人体解刨学
nor did he try to study.
也没有想要试图学习
Right, and he didn't even bother
对 而且他也没有
tidying up the scene.
清理现场
He didn't even try to conceal evidence.
他甚至没有想要隐藏证据
So we could say that
所以我们可以说
Chase's murders were unsystematic.
蔡斯的案子是没有系统的
He chose his victims at random, and it wasn't premeditated.
他随意选择想要杀害的人 而且并不需要预谋
And even when he was caught at the scene, he was very confused.
即便在现场被抓 他都会非常困惑
On top of that, he suffered from schizophrenia.
除此之外他还还有精神分裂症
His cases were typical unsystematic murders.
他的案子是典型的非体系谋杀案
We need a list of your psychiatric patients since 1999.
我们需要你们提供一份自1999年以来 五年内的精神病患者名单
How do you manage to stay stuck in the press room?
你是怎么困在新闻发布室里的？
You're doing field coverage and writing all the articles.
你要做现场报道 还要写所有的文章
I get your passion, but your juniors will hate you.
我知道你很有热情 但你的后辈都会讨厌你的
Aren't we both used to people hating us?
我们不都习惯了被人讨厌吗？
Don't worry.
别担心
Not me.
我可不是
What are you talking about? Your juniors hate you way more.
什么啊？你在后辈里比我更讨人厌
So?
所以呢？
Will you do it for me or not?
你会帮我吗？
We have to catch the serial killer.
我们一定要抓到连坏杀人犯
You know we're busy.
你知道我们很忙的
Come on. Don't be like this.
拜托了 别这样
Of course, Mr. Kwak knows how busy you are.
郭老板当然知道你很忙
He files a report whenever one of his girls goes missing,
他只要有女儿失踪就会报案
but the police don't seem to care,
不过好像警察都不关心
so he's getting all anxious.
所以他变得很焦虑
Good grief.
发什么疯
Hey, over here!
喂 在这里！
He's here.
他来了
This is the detective. Say hello.
这位是刑警 快来问好
Reporter Im has told me a lot about you.
林记者一直跟我说你的事情
Hello, Chief Kim.
你好 金股长
I'm Kwak Man-hyun.
我叫郭万铉
GIRLS IN THEIR TWENTIES
（20多岁小姐带出场）
You didn't have to do this.
你把他带来干吗？
Come on. You two should meet.
真是的 你俩也该见一面吧
-No pressure. -None.
-请别有压力 -不会的
Anyway, pretend not to know me when you see me at the station.
反正你在警察局看到我就假装不认识
I always do. Are you worried I'll suddenly say hi?
我一直这样做的啊 难道你还担心我突然跟你打招呼吗？
Who knows?
谁知道呢？
The one thing I learned while working as a detective
我干警察学到的一件事就是
is that you should never trust anyone.
你不能相信任何人
-What brings you by? -Hello, sir.
-你们怎么来了？ -你好
I haven't been here since the team was bad,
自从小组表现不佳后 我就没来过这里了
and it still looks crummy.
现在看来还是很寒酸
Hey, do you have water?
喂 有水喝吗？
-Water? -Forget it.
-水？ -算了
I can't tell if this is a killer's hideout
我都分不清这里是凶手的藏身之所
or a hideout to catch killers.
还是一个用来抓凶手的地方
Are you here to pick a fight?
你怎么一来就找茬？
Hey, those red marks.
喂 那些红色的标记
What are they about?
它们是什么东西？
Today is the 154th day after the first case broke out.
今天是第一起案件发生后的第154天
The 105th day since we put out the APB on him.
是我们发布公开通缉的第105天
You guys even remember your families' birthdays?
你们都记得各自家人的生日吗？
Leave if you're going to stop us.
如果你是来阻止我们的 那就请回吧
Kicking me out already?
已经在下逐客令了吗？
Why else would the chief of the Special Crime Squad be here?
否则机搜队的股长怎么会来这里？
Goodness. Are you a psychic or what?
你还是给我备个座位吧
A scary wolf is roaming around inside the rabbit burrow.
一匹可怕的狼在兔子洞里四处游走
We won't stop until we catch the wolf.
不抓住那匹狼我们就誓不罢手
End of discussion.
不用再说了
Fine. I heard you.
好的 我知道了
Just be careful and stay out of Bong-sik and Captain Yoon's sight.
不过还是要小心点 尽量别去奉植和尹组长眼前瞎晃
You're the chief of the team, yet you always walk on eggshells.
一个机搜队长 干吗一直看人眼色？
What? Do you not walk on eggshells around your juniors?
什么？ 难道你不用看自己晚辈们的眼色吗？
Captain Yoon is one thing,
就算尹组长这样
but Bong-sik has such a nasty temper.
可奉植的脾气实在太差了
I do too.
我也是有脾气的
What do you say? Should I go ahead and load my gun?
你怎么说？要我直接拿枪上膛吗？
That lunatic will actually pull the trigger.
那个疯子是真敢扣扳机啊
That's the problem.
这才是问题的关键
He's been on everyone's case with that temper of his.
办所有人的案子他都这个脾气
Still, we can't just sit back and do nothing.
可我们不能坐视不管
We don't know when the murder will start.
我们不知道凶手会在什么时候行动
It's not like I don't know that! Damn it.
说得像是我不知道一样！见鬼
My head hurts.
我头疼了
I'm leaving. This place is giving me a headache again.
我要走了 来这里就又头疼了
Would you like some tea…
要喝点茶吗…
Thanks for asking me so damn early.
感谢你现在才想起来请我喝茶
Why are you getting mad at that nice kid?
你干吗要对一个友善的小伙子生气？
Goodness, taking your teammate's side?
天啊 还要站自己队友的边？
Be good. I'm watching you.
好好干 我看着呢
Goodbye.
再见
So why were you really here?
所以你到底来这里干吗？
I came because I missed you. Happy?
我是来看你的 高兴了吗？
Goodbye.
再见
I'm sure you were here to nag me!
我知道你是来唠叨我的！
A hundred and five days?
105天了吗？
Those stubborn wackos.
这群固执的疯子
Hello.
你好
Yoon Tae-gu of Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency.
我是首尔地方警察厅的尹泰九
-I heard you have information. -Yes, I called.
-我听说你这里有消息 -是我打的电话
Hey!
喂！
What are you doing?
你干吗？
What's with you?
你怎么了？
We're detectives.
我们是首尔警察厅的刑警
Is that so?
是吗？
-I'm sorry. -Okay, fine.
-对不起 -没关系
Darn it.
见鬼
The train is approaching.
列车即将进站
Please step behind the safety line.
请站在安全线后面
Do you think we live with pointless anxiety?
你觉得我们生活在 毫无意义的焦虑中吗？
It comes with the job.
职业病罢了
HAN JONG-YONG, YOON JUNG-YOON
（韩钟镛 尹正允）
-Gosh, it's pouring. -It's cold.
-天啊 雨太大了 -真冷
-Hello.
-你好 -你们好
-Are you two coming in? -Yes.
-你们回来了啊？ -是的
-Are you going out? -To the market.
-你要出门？ -去餐厅
Look what you've got there.
小心一点
This is really good.
真的太好吃了
-Anyway. -Yes?
-不过… -嗯？
"Is this the police's lifeline or is this the beginning of doom?"
“这是警察的救命稻草 还是厄运的开始？”
That one was harsh.
这句话太苛刻了
It's true. What about it?
事实如此啊 有问题吗？
Inspector Song doesn't show it,
虽然宋警卫没有表露
but he's already in a tight spot after he put out the APB.
可是在公开通缉后 他的处境真的不太好
So who on earth is this Inspector Song?
所以这个宋警卫究竟是何许人也？
One of the two people I respect the most.
是我最尊敬的两个人中的一个
Behavioral Analysis Team?
犯罪行为分析组？
The profiler?
那个侧写师？
Yes.
是的
After what Inspector Song said to me on my first day,
在我第一天上班 宋警卫对我说了那些话之后
I never regretted joining this team.
我从来没有后悔加入这个团队
What did he say?
他说了什么？
He asked me that day why I applied for this team.
那天他问我为什么申请来这个团队
Nothing really came to my mind, so I immaturely replied,
我什么都没想过 于是就很不成熟地回答说
"Because it seemed cool."
“因为这看起来很酷”
And he said,
过了一会儿他回我
Do you know the story of the blind man and a lantern?
你知道盲人提灯笼的故事吗？
Someone asked a blind man who was walking down a dark road
一位盲人走在黑暗的小路上
with a lantern in his hand.
手里提着一盏灯笼
"You can't see anyway. Why do you carry that around?"
“你又看不见 提着灯笼走来走去干吗？”
Why do you think so?
你怎么看？
He wanted others to see clearly
他想让别人走路时
and not fall down while walking.
能看清楚 不会摔跤
I see. That's touching.
确实很帅呢
A lantern.
一盏灯笼
VICTIMS: HAN SEOK-HOON, YANG KYUNG-HEE
（受害者：韩世勋 杨庆熙）
KWON HYUN-SOOK, 54, FEMALE
（权贤淑 54岁女性）
Then tell me his name too.
告诉我他的名字吧
-Inspector Song Ha-young. -Song Ha-young?
-宋霞永警卫 -宋霞永？
-Honey. -Hey.
-亲爱的 -嗯
-Did you wait for long? -I just got off.
-你等很久了吗？ -我刚下车
-It's raining a lot. -Yes.
-雨下得真大啊 -是啊
Can you put it in here?
能帮我放进来吗？
-Yes. Thank you. -Sure.
-好的 谢谢 -不客气
-Enjoy. -Goodbye.
-请好好享用 -再见
My gosh, why is it raining so much?
天啊 怎么下这么大的雨？
I'm home.
我回来了
Mom?
妈妈？
The receiver cannot be reached.
您拨打的电话暂时无法接通
I'm sorry. I'm late.
对不起 我来晚了
Why didn't you pick up your phone?
为什么不接电话？
I left it at the bakery.
我把手机落在面包店了
When I went back, they were already closed.
我回去拿的时候 他们已经关门了
You didn't have to get this.
你不用非得去买这些
And from now on, tell me to get these.
从现在开始 让我去买这些东西吧
No.
不用
I'm much better than you at picking out ingredients.
我可比你更擅长挑选食材
Goodness, I'm glad I made the soup earlier.
天啊 还好我事先煲好了汤
Honey, you should also celebrate Ha-young's birthday with us.
老公 你也要祝我们霞永生日快乐啊
The sky is blue, and cherry blossoms are in full blossom.
天空湛蓝 樱花盛开
The weather continues to stay nice and makes us feel warm.
持续晴朗的天气让我们感受到了温暖
The temperature will rise tomorrow,
明天的气温会有所上升
and it'll be a bit hotter in the south like early summer.
南部地区会像初夏那样变得更热一些
But the air is a bit drier.
不过空气也会变得更干燥些
In Chungcheong and Gangwon…
在忠清道和江原道…
-What's that? -The daily case report.
-这是什么？ -每日案件报告
I said we won't return to the office after visiting the prison,
我说我们去完监狱就不回办公室了
and Woo-ju gave these to me.
然后宇宙就给了我这些
Where did we find a such treasure like that kid?
我们上哪去找这样的宝藏青年啊？
I still have good luck with people.
我在遇人方面还是很有运气的
Am I included in that luck?
我也包括在你的运气里吧？
Why? Do you think you aren't?
怎么了？担心自己不是吗？
You're worried over nothing.
你可什么都不用担心
-Nothing, right? -No.
-没什么事吧？ -是啊
I'm not sure if that's good, or if finding something is good.
我不知道没事是好事 还是发现点什么事才是好事
I wouldn't feel so frustrated only if we could figure out
如果我们能确定他是收手了 还是改变作案手法了的话
if he stopped or changed his MO.
我就不会觉得郁闷了
"Mugging in a residential area,
在居民区抢劫
stabbed in the left side, serious injury inflicted by the stab…"
身体左侧被刺 严重的刀刺伤口
"Camping knife"?
“野营用刀？”
-Camping knife? -Yes.
-野营用刀？ -对
Why?
怎么了？
May I see that again?
我能再看一下吗？
-Which one? Sinheung 4-dong? -Yes.
-哪个？新兴四洞？ -对
It's just an assault case.
这只是个暴力袭击案
-May I see it? -Which one?
-我能看一下吗？ -哪一个？
"April 15, 3:30 a.m. A residential area, in public.
“4月15号凌晨3点半 住宅区 公共场合”
Victim, female.
受害者 女性
Serious injury inflicted
身体左侧被刀刺后
by a stab on the left side."
伤势严重
-"Weapon was a camping knife." -Camping knife.
-“凶器是一把野营用刀” -野营用刀
Camping knife.
野营用刀
ATTACKED WITH A CAMPING KNIFE
（用一把野营用刀实行袭击）
Could you please make a call to Woo-ju?
你能打电话给宇宙吗？
Sure. One second.
行 稍等
Hey, Woo-ju.
喂 宇宙
Can you look up "camping knife" and find some reports?
你在报告里搜索一下“野营用刀”
-Camping knife? -Yes, this year.
-野营用刀？ -对 今年的
I remember reading it.
我记得之前读到过
One second.
等一下
You should begin with Dongjak Police Station.
你在铜雀警察局的资料里查一下
2004 DAILY CASE REPORT
（2004年每日案件报告）
CAMPING KNIFE
（野营用刀）
-Two cases popped up. -Two cases?
-发现了两起案件 -两起案件？
Yes. In Sinheung 5-dong and Sinheung 2-dong.
是的 在新兴五洞和新兴二洞
Both cases are from February this year.
案子都是今年2月的
Tell me about the victims.
跟我说说受害者
Both of them were women in their twenties.
两个都是20几岁的女性受害者
And they have serious injuries.
而且她们都有严重的伤口
Both were categorized as assaults.
两起都被归类为袭击案
Print the case reports.
把案件报告打印出来
Let's go.
我们走
Captain Yoon.
尹组长
Did you look into it?
你去调查了吗？
The cases in Guo-dong and Borim-dong took place in January and February.
于1月份和2月份分别发生在 久梧洞和宝林洞的案件
Captain Yoon.
尹组长
Do you think it's the same guy?
你觉得会是同一个家伙吗？
Both victims had serious injuries.
两名受害者都有严重的伤口
They were reported as assault cases.
它们都被报告为袭击案
Neither of the victims can remember his face?
没有受害者记得他的脸吗？
They remember seeing him running away from the back.
我们只记得看他转身逃跑的背影
Both victims said that he was short and had a small build.
两名受害者都说他身材矮小
But it might be a bit of a leap
但要说她们是被同一个人袭击的
to say that they were attacked by the same guy.
还太过鲁莽
But the wealthy senior citizen murders happened in different districts.
但是谋杀富有老人案 都是发生在不同地区的
But even if we assume that his MO changed,
即便我们假设他改变了作案手法
it's still confusing because the victims didn't die.
可因为受害者都没有死 所以还是有些令人疑惑的
Both victims were
两名受害者
stabbed in the abdomen by a camping knife.
都被一把野营用刀刺伤了腹部
The same weapon and location of the stab wounds.
使用的凶器和刺伤的部位都一样
Based on this, we can assume that the culprit is the same person.
这样看来的话 我们可以假设罪犯是同一个人
But I'm not sure
但我不确定
if it's enough to report this as criminal intelligence.
如果这足以作为犯罪情报上报的话
This part bothers me the most.
这部分是我最担心的
A suspect who is 170cm with a small build.
一名身高一米七的小个子疑犯
It's similar to the guy we're looking for.
这和我们在找的人很相似
This is from Geumcheon Police Station?
这是金村警察局的案子吗？
Yes. The detective in charge is my friend.
对 负责此案的刑警是我一届的
And we recently had a drink.
我们最近还一起喝过酒
When he told me about this, it felt fishy. So we looked into it.
他跟我说这事的时候感觉有点可疑 所以我们做了调查
What about this?
那怎么了？
At our last meeting, Inspector Song mentioned the possibility
我们上次开会的时候 宋警卫提出了
that he might change his MO.
他改变作案手法的可能性
I remembered what he said that day.
我记得他那天是这样说的
So we kept an eye out to see if there were any cases
所以我们得留心是否还有其他案件
following a pattern.
有类似模式
So these cases
所以这些案件
could have been executed by him?
都有可能出自他的手笔吗？
That's what you mean?
你是这个意思？
Whether it's true or not, it still bothers me.
不管这推断是真是假 我还是很担心
But this isn't a homicide.
可这也不是什么杀人案
It's not enough to take over the cases.
光凭这些也接手不了案子
They are just two assault cases.
它们只是两起袭击案件
Let us investigate this ourselves.
我们自己来调查吧
Goodness. It's all because of this jerk.
天啊 这都怪那个混蛋
I'm starting to see everything as serial murder.
我现在看什么都像连环谋杀案
All cases bring him to my mind.
所有案子都能让我想到他
Same here.
我也是
But these cases don't seem to suit his style.
可是这两起案子不太像是他的风格
Whether it's him or not, if we are suspicious,
不管是不是他干的 只要我们有疑心
we must investigate.
就应该去查清楚
Even if we waste time, that's better than losing him
即便我们在浪费时间
Woo-ju, you got the reports?
宇宙 报告准备好了吗？
Are they important cases?
它们很重要吗？
-We're not sure yet. -Is it him?
-我们还不确定 -难道是他？
There's a small possibility if he changed his MO.
如果他改变作案手法的话 就会有一点可能性
We'll be back. Let's go.
我们先出发了 我们走
We'll be back.
去去就回
The victim is in the hospital now.
受害者现在在医院
She needs to rest.
她需要休息
So you can't meet her.
所以不能见她
-This is her statement. -Okay.
-这是她的陈述 -好
He kept following her,
他一直跟着她
so she threw him her purse.
所以她就朝他扔了她的手提包
But he wasn't interested.
可是他并不在意
How did you confirm it was a camping knife?
你怎么确定那是一把野营用刀？
Given the size of the stab wound, we knew it wasn't a kitchen knife.
从刺伤的伤口大小来看 我们就知道它不是厨房用刀
The victim also said that the knife was small.
受害者也说那把刀很小
The size was about half of our palm.
大小只有我们手掌一半左右
I showed her a few photos.
我给她看了几张照片
And she chose camping knives.
然后她选了野营用刀
-Was there an eyewitness? -Yes.
-现场有目击证人吗？ -有的
He heard screams, so he opened the window and yelled.
他听到了尖叫声 所以开窗大喊
Then the culprit ran away.
然后罪犯就逃跑了
He was short, skinny, balding, and wearing a shabby tracksuit.
他不高、偏瘦、秃头 穿着破旧的运动装
Can we meet with him?
我们能见他吗？
Sure.
当然可以
And what about the other two cases?
那另外两个案子呢？
The other two cases?
另外两个案子？
Two cases with a similar MO took place in February.
在2月发生的两起 作案手法相似的案件
Take a look here.
看一下这里
-Sinheung 5-dong. -Okay.
-新兴五洞 -好的
Sinheung 2-dong.
新兴二洞
You need to ask the team in charge. I don't know about this.
你得问负责案件的那个小组 这个我不知道
He's in charge. Detective Kim, come here.
他是负责人 金刑警 过来这里
He followed her in front of her home.
他尾随她直到她家门口
He stabbed her when she had her key in the hole.
在她插钥匙插的时候 他刺伤了她
He sounded like a total nutcase.
他听起来就像个疯子
Did he try to steal her wallet?
他试图偷她钱包了吗？
After stabbing her, he left without touching her bag.
在刺伤她后 他并没有动她的包 就直接离开了
So the victim was about to go in.
所以当时受害者正要走进家门
And the bastard jumped on her.
然后那个混蛋就跳到了她身后
Then he turned her around.
把她转过来之后
And he started stabbing.
他就开始捅她了
She couldn't remember his face as she was shocked.
她当时太惊恐了 所以记不清他的脸
She said he was short. Right.
她说他不高 没错
He was about 170cm tall.
他身高大约170厘米
Not having security cameras in a blind spot like this
在这样的视野盲区没装监控摄像头
is always a problem.
一直是个问题
But we have more than last year.
但是比去年多了很多
This is an improvement.
情况算是在好转了
Right. That's good.
对 很好
-But we still need more. -Right.
-可我们需要更多 -没错
-Is that the house? -Yes. The second floor.
-是那间房子吗？ -是的 在二楼
That's where I screamed.
就是在那里喊的
Where was the culprit?
罪犯当时在哪里？
Over there. Under the streetlamp.
在那里 街灯下面
Something seemed off, so I was watching them.
似乎哪里不太对劲 所以我当时就看着他们
All of a sudden, the woman started screaming.
突然那个女人开始尖叫
So I screamed, "Hey! What are you doing?"
所以我也大喊起来 “喂！你在干吗？”
When I screamed,
在我大喊的时候
he ran away. And he was really fast.
他逃跑了 他跑得可真快啊
You also said that he was short.
你说过他并不高
He was short.
他有点矮
He was losing hair. He had a bald spot.
他有脱发现象 头顶是秃的
Didn't he wear hiking shoes?
他没有穿登山鞋吗？
I'm not sure about that.
这我不确定
Right. You were pretty far.
对 你隔得太远了
What do you mean by he was fast?
你说他很快是什么意思？
The light was bright, so I could see him running away.
灯光很亮 送一我能看到他逃跑
Enough for you to see he was a fast runner?
亮到你能看清他跑步很快吗？
Yes. I was surprised by how fast he was.
是的 看到他的跑步速度我都惊呆了
The victim suspected it could've been an act of retaliation.
受害者怀疑是不是被人损坏了
So we assumed it could've been an acquaintance.
所以我们猜想有可能是熟人作案
We started questioning her friends.
我们开始询问她的朋友
You didn't find any fingerprints or evidence for either case?
两起案件都没有找到任何指纹或 其他什么证据吗？
Right. He followed her to her house like he was determined to attack her.
没错 他尾随她到她家 就好像他决意要袭击她一样
She wasn't sure if he was following her.
她当时不确定他是否在尾随自己
But he came into the building too.
但是他也进了大楼
And he took something out of his jacket
而且他从他的夹克衫里拿出了什么
and stabbed her right away.
就开始马上捅她了
This case took place in Guo-dong.
这起案件发生在久梧洞
But it's the same MO with Borim-dong.
但是与在宝林洞案件的作案手法一样
The location changed, but still no evidence.
地点不一样 但仍旧没有证据
On top of that, it rained that day.
而且那天还下雨了
A camping knife, a stab wound to the abdomen,
一把野营用刀 一处腹部的刺伤
and no valuables or money were taken.
没带走任何钱财或贵重物品
She didn't know she was being followed because of the rain.
因为天下雨 所以她不知道自己被跟踪了
The victim was on the ground.
受害者躺倒在地上
When he saw a car coming,
他看到有辆车开过来
he was surprised and ran away.
他就慌忙逃跑了
The descriptions are similar.
他们的描述都差不多啊
-But no luck yet? -He was short.
-还是没有发现吗？ -他个子不高
And when she was on the ground, she saw his feet.
她在倒地后 看到了他的脚
He was wearing sneakers.
他穿着运动鞋
Not hiking shoes?
不是登山鞋吗？
She said he wore sneakers.
她说他穿着运动鞋
Sneakers.
运动鞋
The fact that he didn't take money or valuables bothers me the most.
他没有拿走钱财或贵重物品 是最让我感觉奇怪的
Right?
对吧？
He committed crimes in January and February.
他在1月和2月作案两次
It's April, but he hasn't committed any crimes since.
现在是4月 可他至今不再有新的犯案
Is this the cooling-off period the Analysis Team mentioned?
这就是犯罪行为分析组所说的 冷却期吗？
Let's check the scene first.
我们先去查看现场
Is this the place?
是这里吗？
Yes, it is.
就是这里
-This is way too bright. -I know, right?
-这也太亮了吧 -我也觉得
That's odd.
真奇怪
Three people with serious stab wounds from a camping knife after being attacked.
三人都在遭遇袭击后 被野营用刀严重刺伤
All of them took place late at dawn.
案件都发生在黎明时分
All of the victims were young women.
受害者都是年轻女性
The only difference is that one was in an alley.
唯一的不同是一个是在小巷里
The other two were in front of houses.
另外两个是在受害者房门前
They were attacked in different locations, but having three cases with the same MO
她们被袭击的部位并不相同 但是三起案件的作案手法却是一样的
implies that there might be more cases.
这就意味着可能会有新的案件发生
And all of the victims were stabbed in their stomachs.
而且所有受害者都是腹部被刺伤
Do you think it's him?
你觉得会是他吗？
I doubt it.
我不确定
The weapon, MO, and time don't match at all.
凶器 作案手法和时间都完全不一样
But they seem to have a similar build.
不过他们的身形看起来很相似
Right. That's why we can't be certain.
没错 所以我们才无法确定
But he was a fast runner.
不过他跑步很快
If he was visibly fast, I don't think he could've done that in hiking boots.
如果他跑得是显而易见地快 我想他是不可能穿登山鞋的
Right. You can't run fast in hiking boots.
对啊 穿登山鞋是跑不快的
There's a photo of him from behind, and we know he wore hiking boots.
有一张他的背影照片 而且我们知道他是穿登山鞋的
He won't wear them.
他就不会再穿了吧
But the guy we're looking for
但是我们在找的家伙
killed victims with a blunt weapon without giving them a chance to resist.
是用钝器杀死受害者 丝毫不给他们抵抗的余地
Even if he changed his MO,
就算他改变了作案手法
I don't think he would use such a small knife.
我也不觉得他会用一把那么小的刀
Let's say that it is him.
如果说凶手就是他
All of these assault cases would be attempted murder cases.
所有这些袭击案都会成为杀人未遂案
It won't be enough for him.
对他来说一定是不满足的
So he wouldn't have used the same weapon three times.
所以他也不会三次都用相同的凶器
He repeated his crimes.
他在重复犯罪
That means he didn't check if the victim was dead, right?
也就是说他没有确认 受害者是否已经遇害 对吗？
But that doesn't change anything.
可是这不会改变任何事实
He barely left any evidence after breaking into the houses.
他破门而入后 几乎没有留下任何证据
Following his victims?
跟踪他的受害者？
There could've been witnesses. He wouldn't take risks like that
可能会有目击证人 他不会如此冒险
because he's super careful.
因为他非常谨慎
What if it's not him?
如果不是他呢？
Since all the victims were injured,
因为所有受害者都只是受伤
we're not looking for a murderer, but a violent man who robs people.
我们找的不是一个杀人凶手 而是个暴力劫匪
No. He wasn't interested in valuables. He's not a robber.
不会的 他对钱财并不关心 他不是抢劫犯
What if it's what we speculated?
如果就像我们所推测的那样呢？
What if the victims were only injured…
如果受害者没有丧命
because he failed to finish the job?
是因为他失手了呢？
Then…
那么…
we have two serial killers in this country.
我们这个国家就有两个连环杀人犯了
GIRLS IN THEIR TWENTIES
（20多岁小姐带出场）
This one didn't die either?
她也没死？
The same weapons were used.
这三起案子都是同一种凶器
"A camping knife"?
“野营用刀”？
Look, these three locations aren't far from one another.
看这里和这里 这三个地点距离不远
The weapon, where the victims were attacked,
凶器 受害者遭袭击的身体部位
and even the time. These cases have a lot in common.
以及犯案时间都有很多相同点
"Seriously injured…"
“重伤…”
Why?
怎么了？
Is it because they aren't murders?
因为不是杀人案吗？
Is there something else?
还有别的顾虑吗？
Where are you going?
你去哪里？
Captain Yoon, come here for a moment.
尹组长 过来一下
Guo-dong and Borim-dong.
久梧洞和宝林洞
These cases took place in January and February of this year.
这几个案子是在今年1月和2月发生的
We believe these were done by the culprit of the serial murders.
我们相信这些都是 杀害富有老人的连环杀人犯所为
We're investigating at the moment.
我们现在正在调查
It's not the same guy.
不是同一个人
What?
什么？
It's a different guy.
凶手另有其人
His build is similar.
他们身形相似
Other than that, they have nothing else in common.
除此之外 他们毫无共同点可言
From the MO to the weapons, everything's different.
从作案手法到凶器 全部都不一样
Didn't you say the MO could change?
你不是说作案手法可以改变的吗？
Yes, it could change.
手法虽然是可以改变的
But he already got a taste of using blunt weapons.
但他用钝器已经尝到了杀人的快感
He won't change his weapon to something smaller.
他不会把自己的凶器换小的
Then there's less chance this guy is a serial killer.
那这家伙是连环杀人犯的 可能性就更小了
These victims didn't die.
这些受害者都没死
Thankfully, they're alive.
谢天谢地 她们都还活着
But it could actually make the culprit even more violent.
但这可能会使罪犯变得更暴力
We must catch him before there's another victim.
我们一定要在他 实施下一次行动之前阻止他
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
This serial killer is already giving us a huge headache.
这个连环杀人犯 已经够让我们头痛的了
How will we track down a murder that hasn't even happened yet?
要怎么抓到还没杀人的连环杀人犯
Let's draw a facial composite.
我们来做罪犯画像吧
Yes, let's start with a facial composite.
对 我们先从罪犯画像开始
All the victims are alive.
所有受害者都活着
We have a witness too.
我们还有目击证人
The victims are traumatized and don't remember his face.
受害者有过心灵创伤 记不清他的脸
Let's try forensic hypnosis.
试试司法催眠吧
He has a slim face.
他的脸很瘦
USE OF HYPNOSIS IN THE INVESTIGATIVE PROCESS TO FIND CLUES
（司法催眠：运用催眠术寻找线索）
He has small, slanted eyes.
他有一双小眯眼
And…
还有…
Right.
对了
He was somewhat bald.
他有点秃头
Where? The forehead?
哪里秃？是前额吗？
Yes.
对
NATIONAL FORENSICS SERVICE
（国立科学搜查研究院）
As you know, the killer isn't after money.
正如你所言 凶手的目的不是钱
FACIAL COMPOSITE RESULT
（罪犯画像结果）
If it's not about money or grudges,
如果不是出于钱财或怨恨
there can be only one purpose.
那就只有一个目的
Killing.
杀人
Yes, he looked somewhat like this.
对 他看起来就像这样
He was skinny, so he had a slim face like this.
他很精瘦 所以有一张像这样的瘦脸
This is pretty accurate.
画得很像啊
-Thank you. -No problem.
-谢谢 -不客气
Let's go.
我们走
You're here.
你们来了啊
Take a look at this.
看看这个吧
We had the witness verify the accuracy of this composite.
我们找了目击证人核实画像的准确度
Looks good, right?
看着不错吧？
So this scum may be the one who killed the senior citizens.
所以这个混蛋可能就是那个 谋杀富有老人的家伙
It's not the same guy.
他们不是同一个人
No.
不是的
We'll continue to investigate based on the possibility of him
我们会基于他们是同一个人的假设
being the same guy.
继续进行调查
Whether it's the same guy or not,
不管是不是同一个人
we're investigating the same case, aren't we?
我们都在调查同一个案子不是吗？
-Yes, we are. -Very well.
-是的 -很好
-Let's go through it again. -Okay.
-我们重新过一遍 -好
It took place late at night
案子是在深夜
under a brightly lit streetlamp.
明亮的街灯下发生的
The Borim-dong case also took place under a streetlamp.
宝林洞案也是在街灯下发生的
Normally, suspects look for dark spots to hide.
通常情况下 嫌疑人会找昏暗的地点藏身
And the victims were attacked from the front, not from behind.
而且受害者是从前面 而非身后遭受袭击的
Did he reveal his face on purpose?
他是要故意露脸吗？
-Hold on. Watch this. -Okay.
-等一等 看看这个 -嗯
The victim
受害者
was walking this way.
超这个方向走着
She suddenly felt that someone was following her.
她突然察觉到有人在跟踪她
She threw her purse, so he'd take it and leave.
她扔下了自己的钱包 所以他可以拿着钱包离开
But he didn't care about the purse and kept following her,
可他并不在意钱包 而是继续跟着她
so she started walking faster, terrified.
所以她开始感到害怕 并走得更快了
The culprit must've continued to follow her.
罪犯一定继续尾随她
Then he suddenly
然后他突然
swung his knife at her.
向她挥起了他的刀
-Hold on. -He made her turn around on purpose.
-等一下 -他是故意让她转过来的
But it could've happened the moment she happened to turn around.
但也有可能是在她 正巧转过身来的时候发生的
One commonality of these cases is that
这些案子的一个共同之处是
their abdomen was stabbed.
她们的腹部都被刺伤
They were stabbed from the front.
她们是从前面被捅刀的
They took place in the southwestern part.
案子都是发生在西南部地区
Maybe he lives in the area.
可能他生活在那一带
Why does the Special Crime Squad think these cases
为什么机搜队的人会认为这些案子
were committed by the culprit who killed the rich senior citizens?
都是那个谋杀富有老人的罪犯干的？
That scum targeted luxurious houses
那个混蛋的目标是江南和江北的
in Gangnam and Gangbuk.
豪华住宅
But as you can see on this map,
但你能从这张地图上看出
this isn't a rich neighborhood.
这里可不是富裕的社区
Let's go through everything again.
我们来把所有事重新过一遍
Our theory is that
我们的理论是
he attacked the victims to kill them.
他袭击受害者是为了杀人
And these attacks took place
这样的袭击在首尔的西南地区
five times in southwestern Seoul.
一共发生了五次
That could mean he didn't know that the victims didn't die.
这就可能意味着他不知道受害者没死
Will his MO change when he finds out they didn't die?
当他发现她们没死之后 他会改变作案手法吗？
It's highly likely.
非常有可能
If he didn't know they didn't die,
如果他不知道她们没有死
and if that was why he kept using the same MO,
而且如果这就是他一直使用 相同作案手法的原因
these "attacks" could turn into murders once he finds out.
那么这些“袭击”就有可能在他 发现真相后变成谋杀
In fact, that is what I'm most worried about.
事实上这才是我最担心的
Then how would he find out?
那他怎么知道的呢？
Through the news or the newspapers, probably.
可能通过电视新闻或者报纸
Or he could visit the scenes again.
又或者他可以回到现场
You said it rained when the attack took place.
你说袭击发生的时候天在下雨
Yes.
是的
You can't see clearly when it's raining, which makes it easier
下雨的时候你很难看清东西 这就使犯罪
to commit crimes.
变得更加容易
On top of choosing a brightly lit spot,
除了选择一个明亮的地点
he purposely revealed his face. Why?
他还故意露出了自己的脸 为什么？
This wasn't about a personal grudge, so why did he reveal his face?
这与个人怨恨无关 所以他为什么要露脸呢？
Why? Why did he do that?
为什么？他为什么要那么做？
I really don't get it.
我真想不通
What time did the incident take place?
意外是在什么时间发生的呢？
Around 9 p.m.
大概在晚上9点左右
-Let's go back to the scene in Borim-dong. -Yes, ma'am.
-我们回去宝林洞现场看一看吧 -好的
So we'll check this area every day from now on, right?
所以从今往后 我们每天都要来这里打卡了吗？
Yes.
对
Do you really think the culprit will return to the scene?
你真的认为罪犯会重新回来现场吗？
First, we have to put ourselves in his shoes.
首先 我们应该站在他的角度看问题
Why did he choose these areas?
他为什么选择这些地点？
Did he look for easy spots
他是在找
where he can attack and run?
方便他下手后逃跑的地点吗？
Or is he familiar with this area?
还是他对这一带更熟悉呢？
Gosh, this feels like a waste of time.
天啊 好茫然啊
I feel like we're on a stakeout
我觉得我们在监视一件
for something that hasn't happened yet.
还没发生的事
No, we're not. We're trying to track down
并非如此 我们是在试图追踪
a serial killer
已经犯下很多案子的
who has already committed murders.
一个连环杀人犯
It is the same case,
虽然是同件案子
but remember that we're looking at it from a different perspective,
但要记住我们是从另一个角度调查的
on the premise that it's the same guy.
我们的假设 罪犯是同一个人
PUREUMAE PARK, DONGJAK-GU
（铜雀区苍鹰公园）
This early morning at Seoul Pureumae Park,
今天清晨在首尔苍鹰公园
a woman in her twenties was found stabbed to death.
一名20多岁的女性被发现被刺身亡
The victim had been stabbed multiple times
受害者被刺数刀
and had already lost a lot of blood when she was found.
被发现时已经失血过多
People were heartbroken to hear she passed away in the ambulance
得知她在去医院路上的救护车上去世
on the way to the hospital.
人们都非常难过
The crime occurred at a blind spot where there were no security cameras.
犯罪发生在一个没有摄像头的地方
It's been a struggle to find traces of the culprit due to a lack of witnesses.
由于没有目击者 寻找罪犯踪迹变得非常困难
The importance of having safety measures in parks
人们开始意识到
has been raised.
提高公园安全措施的重要性
Seoul City has announced that they will inspect the parks' streetlamps
首尔市宣布 他们将检查公园路灯
and install more security cameras to remove blind spots.
并安装更多的监控摄像头 以消除视野盲点
MAP OF SEOUL
（首尔地图）
The Pureumae Case also occurred in the southwestern district.
苍鹰公园案同样发生在西南地区
This happened at a park though, not a residential street.
但是这次事故是发生在公园 而不是居住区街道
And the weapon wasn't a camping knife but a kitchen knife.
凶器也不是野营用刀 而是厨房用刀
You're seeing this as the same guy when it's this different?
都那么大区别了 你还要说犯罪是同一个人吗？
Or is it a third suspect?
还是说有第三个嫌疑人？
Come on, just hear him out.
拜托了 先听他说完吧
Carry on.
继续说
A woman in her twenties was stabbed in the abdomen late at night.
20多岁的女性在深夜被人捅伤腹部
The time of the crime and area of attack match the other victims.
实施袭击的时间和地点 与其他几个案件都是一致的
Although it's a park,
尽管是在公园
it's a shortcut to the residential area
这是一条通往住宅区的近道
so residents of this neighborhood
所以附近的居民
often use this route.
经常会走这条路
Why does that matter?
这有什么关系呢？
I'm saying, it has to be considered a residential alley.
我是说这里同样可以被视作是 一条居民区的小巷
We have a description of the suspect too.
我们还有对嫌疑人的描述
Wait, there was a witness?
等等 有目击证人吗？
No.
不是的
The victim gave testimony while being transported by ambulance.
受害者在被救护车运送时作出了描述
I guess…
我想
she was alive up until then.
那个时候她还是活着的
It was a man in his thirties, about 170cm in height
是一名30多岁的男性 身高约170厘米
with little hair,
头发稀少
dressed in dark workout clothes.
穿着深色运动服
In a phone call with her boyfriend right after the incident, she said,
事故发生之后她立刻打电话给男友说
"A stranger followed me and stabbed me with a knife."
“有个陌生人跟踪我 他拿刀捅了我”
The conversation ended with that.
对话就那样结束了
Just as we feared,
正如我们所担心的
the culprit wasn't satisfied with his last crime.
罪犯对他之前的犯案并不满意
We assumed he committed another crime with a larger and sharper weapon.
我们猜测他会用更大且锋利的武器 实施新的犯罪活动
-I still disagree. -With what?
-我还是不赞成 -理由？
I disagree with everything that the Analysis Team says.
只要是分析组说的东西 我就都反对
Don't you think it's time we stop being swayed by them?
你不觉得现在是时候 我们不该再被他们所左右了吗？
-Damn it. -Gosh, that temper of his.
-见鬼 -天啊 他这个臭脾气
Just let him be.
随他去吧
So then the Analysis Team thinks
所以说分析组的意思是
that the culprit of the Southwest Case
西南部案件的罪犯
and this one is the same guy, right?
这次犯案的家伙是同一个人对吗？
Yes. If you take a look at the pictures from the scene,
对 如果你仔细看一看 从现场拍回来的照片
it's neither sexual assault nor mugging.
这既不是性侵犯也不是抢劫
It's a different guy from the serial murders of the rich elderly then?
那就是说这个人不是谋杀富有老人的 那个连环杀人犯？
Yes.
对
I don't want to say this,
虽然我也不想这么说
but we have to catch
但是我们得追捕
two serial killers.
两名连环杀人犯了
Don't blow this matter up hastily.
别急着把这事情闹大
If we announce
如果我们在没有明确证据的情况下
there are two serial killers without clear evidence,
就此宣布有两名连环杀人犯的话
the level of anxiety the public feel will only multiply.
只会加剧公众的焦虑情绪
Their trust in the police will also waver.
他们对警察的信任也会动摇
Physical evidence found at the scene is not the only clue.
在现场发现的物证并不是唯一的线索
There are bound to be traces in the time and place he resided that day.
他在那天出现的时间和地点 一定会有痕迹的
A trace that may seem trivial
即便是看起来微不足道的痕迹
becomes an important clue.
都会成为重要线索
We can't only look at the weapon, but we must expand the conditions
我们不能只关注凶器 而要扩大范围
and look to see if there are any similar cases.
找一找是否有任何相似的案件
So?
所以呢？
You want us to request cooperation from the 31 police stations in Seoul?
你想让我们请求 首尔31所警察分局的合作吗？
I think if we can, we must do it.
我想如果可以的话 我们必须这么做
SPECIAL CRIME SQUAD 1, TEAM 1
（机动搜查队一科一组）
-Is he serious? -Seriously?
-他认真的吗？ -说真的吗？
We have so much to do.
我们还有很多事要做呢
-Gosh. -This is nonsense.
-天啊 -真是胡闹
The Seoul Metropolitan Police Agency and the Special Crime Squad
首尔地方警察厅和机搜队
held a meeting with 31 chiefs of police
与31所警察分局召开会议
to solve the serial attacks on women in southwest Seoul.
以侦破首尔西南部的袭击女性连环案
They established an information room for crimes with no motives
他们为无动机的犯罪 设立了一个信息室
and announced they'll be increasing cooperative investigations.
并宣布他们会加强合作调查
We are a personal bodyguard service.
我们是私人保镖服务公司
A bodyguard just for myself--
一个专门保护自己的保镖
Self-defense sprays.
自我防卫喷雾剂
Now offering a huge discount.
现在提供钜惠折扣
The reason is…
原因是…
With violent crimes targeting women happening consecutively
在首尔西南部地区
in the southwestern district of Seoul,
针对女性的暴力犯罪接连发生
the level of anxiety has jumped among the people.
人们的焦虑程度急剧上升
Within this year, there have been six cases of attacks in this area.
就在今年 该地区已发生了六起案件
It's been revealed that one of these cases was a murder
据透露 其中还包括一起谋杀案件
causing huge shock in the community.
并在社区引起巨大惊动
We'll connect to Reporter Kim Ju-young.
我们将连线记者金周英
Past midnight on the 16th at Pureumae Park,
16号午夜过后
a murder occurred.
苍鹰公园发生了一起谋杀案
Pureumae Park is looking empty
由于没有游客来访
due to no visitors coming by.
苍鹰公园看起来空无一人
One citizen expressed her anxiety by saying,
一民市民表达了她的恐惧并说道
"I'm scared to walk alone, so I'm refraining from going out."
“我害怕一个人走路 所以都在尽量避免外出”
The police have increased the amount of questioning
警方加大寻访力度
and have been doing their best in trying to obtain evidence.
并在竭尽全力试图查找证据
But they haven't made much progress.
但是他们尚未取得明显成果
LOOKING FOR WITNESSES 10 MILLION WON REWARD
（寻找证人 悬赏1000万韩元）
Another late night for you.
今天又那么晚
You must be tired.
一定很努力吧？
-Are you going to morning mass? -Yes.
-你要去做清晨祷告了吗？ -嗯
I'll drop you off.
我送你过去吧
Gosh, it's fine. I go there every week anyway.
天啊 不用了 反正我每周都会去那里
It's bright outside. Don't worry.
外面天都亮了 不用担心
No, I'll drop you off. Come on out.
不 还是我送你过去吧 出来吧
My goodness. I told you, it's fine.
我的天啊 说了我会没事的
Please think of your servant Michael
请想想你的仆人迈克尔
whom you called away from this world.
你把他从这个世界叫走了
He participated in the saint's death
他通过洗礼
through baptism.
参与了圣徒的死亡
So please let him enjoy his resurrection too.
所以也请让他重新复活吧
Those who are asleep with hopes…
那些抱着希冀长眠的人…
The devil has yet again disappeared without a trace.
魔鬼又消失得无影无踪了
Please think of them
请想想他们
and let them meet your shining face.
让他们看到您光辉的面庞吧
JULY 2004
（2004年6月）
Why are they under construction every day?
为什么他们每天都在施工？
They're going to build a house soon.
他们马上又要造房子了
The noise is killing me.
噪音真是烦死我了
Police.
我是警察
SENIOR INSPECTOR KOOK YOUNG-SOO
（警监 国荣秀）
Yes.
对
"Spooky Thursdays."
“令人毛骨悚然的周四”
They've stopped night studies at girls' high schools.
女子高中的晚自习已经停掉了
I have nightmares every night because I'm worried
我每天晚上都会做噩梦
this may end up a cold case.
因为我担心这又会变成一桩悬案
I think the world is becoming strange.
我觉得这世界越变越奇怪了
Seriously.
对啊
I feel like I'm running in circles.
我感觉自己一直在兜圈子
What does he want to nag about now?
他又要唠叨什么啊？
Yes?
喂？
Where are you, Young-soo? Hurry up and come in.
荣秀 你在哪里？快回来
-Why? -I think we caught that bastard.
-怎么了？ -我想我们抓到那个混蛋了
"That bastard"? Which one?
“那个混蛋”？是哪个？
That bastard forged your ID card.
那个伪造你身份证的混蛋
Forged ID card? What are you talking about?
伪造身份证？你在说什么？
The one I lost four years ago?
四年前被他跑掉的那个吗？
Damn it! Just shut up and come.
该死！就别问了 快给我回来
The serial killer of the wealthy senior citizen case…
谋杀富有老人的连环杀人犯
We caught that scum!
我们抓到那个家伙了
Turn the car around, Ha-young.
霞永 快掉头
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
（首尔地方警察厅）
PERSONAL INFORMATION
（个人信息）
You arrested him as a suspect of a sex worker's abduction?
你是以绑架性工作者的嫌疑犯 逮捕他的吗？
Yes.
对
The women on the staff couldn't be reached.
因为接连有好几位女性联系不上
The pimp reported him after much suspicion.
皮条客觉得很可疑就报案了
He was arrested around 5:30 a.m. today.
他是在今天早上5点半被捕的
Mapo Police Station is done investigating
嫌疑人具永春的手机
culprit Gu Young-chun's phone,
以及失踪女性的物品
as well as articles from the missing women.
麻浦警察局那边已经调查完毕
We're also searching through the car of the victim
两天前失踪女性的车辆
who went missing two days ago.
也正在进行鉴定
What about the missing victims?
那些失踪的受害者呢？
"I killed them. I didn't."
“我杀了他们 我没杀人”
"I buried them. I didn't."
“我把他们埋了 我没埋”
His statement is inconsistent.
他的陈述前后矛盾
Anyway, how did Chief Kim Bong-sik
话说回来
end up catching him too?
金奉植股长怎么也抓到他了？
The owner of the business, Kwak Man-hyun,
报案的老板郭万铉
is an acquaintance of Chief Kim Bong-sik.
认识金奉植股长
That's why he's not showing up?
所以他才不现身的吗？
Anyway,
无论如何
are you sure that guy said he did all those things
你确定那家伙说了
to the elderly people?
杀害老人的事都是他干的吗？
Yes, I think so.
对 我是这么想的
But he kept going off speaking nonsense
但他在我们来这里的路上
on our way here.
一直废话连篇
What do you think, Inspector Song?
宋警卫你怎么想呢？
We should check
我们应该查一下
if he's mentally ill or has personality disorders.
他是否有精神病或人格障碍